♪Menelan kegelisahan♪
♪메넬란 케겔리사한♪
♪Your roots firmly grip this land♪
♪당신의 뿌리는 이 땅을 굳건히 붙잡고 있습니다♪
♪Mengejar ombak♪
♪멘게자르 옴박♪
♪My leaves cross a distant border♪
♪나의 나뭇잎은 먼 국경을 넘어간다♪
♪Kejauhan Menants♪
♪케자우한 메난츠♪
♪Eternity is the ultimate goal♪
♪영원함이 궁극적인 목표입니다♪
♪Separating again after meeting♪
♪만남 후 또 헤어짐♪
♪Back apart after leaning in♪
♪기대고 뒤로 물러나기♪
♪I never forget♪
♪절대 잊지 않아요♪
♪A sword flash splits the colored sky♪
♪ 색빛 하늘을 가르는 검의 섬광 ♪
♪Abandoned dreams shattered♪
♪버려진 꿈은 산산이 부서졌다♪
♪Breaking through fearlessly♪
♪용맹스럽게 돌파♪
♪Looking at the waves of the anchored sails, the world has changed♪
♪정박된 돛의 파도를 보니 세상이 달라졌다♪
♪Armor and makeup scattered in the air♪
♪갑옷과 화장이 공중에 흩뿌려집니다♪
♪Ever scared, the blood doesn't dry up, and dreaming of twilight♪
♪무서워도 피가 마르지 않고 황혼을 꿈꾸며♪
♪Just wish you were by my side♪
♪당신이 내 곁에 있었으면 좋겠어요♪
♪Youth is not wasted♪
♪청춘은 낭비되지 않는다♪
♪Stand firm, unite with each other, and raise your sword with you♪
♪ 굳건히 서서 서로 뭉쳐 함께 검을 들어라 ♪
♪Seeing sparks fall on our shoulders♪
♪ 우리 어깨에 불꽃이 떨어지는 걸 보니♪
♪There are no regrets in this mortal world♪
♪이 세상엔 후회란 없어♪
=Love Trip=
=사랑여행=
=Episode 5=
=에피소드 5=
(Han Residence)
(한 레지던스)
(Kediaman Han Li)
(케디아만 한리)
The change in your appearance is quite good.
외모의 변화가 꽤 좋습니다.
See you later.
나중에 봐요.
Come on, don't cry.
자, 울지 마세요.
OK, don't cry anymore.
알았어, 더 이상 울지 마.
Why does he keep crying?
그 사람은 왜 계속 울어요?
- Good boy, don't cry. - Do not Cry anymore.
- 착해요, 울지 마세요. - 더 이상 울지 마세요.
Why do you think a new baby was born in a few days ?
왜 며칠 만에 새로운 아기가 태어났다고 생각합니까 ?
Can you experience diarrhea, fever and rashes?
설사, 발열, 발진이 나타날 수 있나요 ?
Could it be that he caught a cold
혹시 감기에 걸린 건 아닐까?
because it was brought out to meet the guests
손님을 맞이하기 위해 나온 것이기 때문에
at the baby bathing banquet today?
오늘 아기 목욕 연회에?
Guard, quickly call a doctor.
경비병님, 빨리 의사를 불러주세요.
- Don't cry, okay? - Don't cry.
- 울지 마, 알았지? - 울지 마세요.
- Ok, it is finished. - Fine, I'll go right away.
- 알았어, 끝났어. - 알았어, 바로 갈게.
OK, don't cry anymore.
알았어, 더 이상 울지 마.
Soon it will be fine. The healer will be here soon.
곧 괜찮을 것입니다. 치료사가 곧 여기에 올 것입니다.
- I'm very anxious. - Don't cry, okay?
- 정말 불안해요. - 울지 마, 알았지?
- Don't cry anymore, okay? - Good boy.
- 더 이상 울지 마세요, 알았죠? - 착한 소년.
- That's it, don't cry anymore. - Very worrying.
-그렇습니다. 더 이상 울지 마십시오. - 매우 걱정스럽습니다.
The healer has arrived, madam.
치료사가 도착했습니다, 부인.
Healer, hurry up. Quickly check what happened to him.
힐러님, 서둘러주세요. 그에게 무슨 일이 일어났는지 재빨리 확인해 보세요 .
This.
이것.
(Han Li, Bawahan Sun Jingdan Gubernur Bingzhou)
(한 리, Bawahan Sun Jingdan Gubernur Bingzhou)
A very brave criminal.
매우 용감한 범죄자입니다.
How dare he sneak into the residence
그 사람이 어떻게 감히 숙소에 몰래 들어왔지?
when there are many guests at the baby's bathing event
아기 목욕 행사에 손님이 많을 때
and kidnapped my grandson!
그리고 내 손자를 납치했어요!
He also left messages openly
공개적으로 메시지도 남겼다
and asked me to exchange it for Military Plates.
그리고 군용 플레이트로 교환해달라고 하더군요 .
Please calm down, Mr. Big.
진정하세요, 빅 씨.
Be careful when dealing with bad people.
나쁜 사람을 대할 때는 조심하세요 .
Chengzhi, menuutmu,
청지, 메뉴웃무,
who dares to do this?
누가 감히 이런 일을 하겠느냐?
(Lv Chengzhi, Advisor to Han Li) The Western Border Army just now
(Lv Chengzhi, Han Li 고문) 방금 서부 국경군
was defeated in Wangzhou City and is not far from us.
왕저우(Wangzhou)시에서 패배했고 우리와 멀지 않습니다.
Young Master Cui of the Cui Family Team also led the team around here.
Cui Family Team의 Young Master Cui 도 이곳에서 팀을 이끌었습니다.
Now, both families had their eyes set on Bingzhou.
이제 두 가족 모두 Bingzhou에 눈을 떴습니다.
There is no need to worry about the Western Border Army
서부 국경군은 걱정할 필요가 없습니다
who lost his family.
가족을 잃은 사람.
It's just that Young Master Cui is quite troublesome.
단지 Young Master Cui가 꽤 귀찮은 것뿐입니다 .
Currently, he had kidnapped the Little Young Master
현재 그는 Little Young Master를 납치했습니다.
and told us to put on Military Plates
그리고 우리에게 군용 번호판을 쓰라고 했어요
in the forest outside the city.
도시 외곽의 숲에서.
Otherwise, they will hurt Little Young Master.
그렇지 않으면 꼬마 스승님에게 상처를 줄 것입니다.
Give them fake Military Plates .
가짜 군용 번호판을 주세요.
Good.
좋은.
Luckily you pretended to be a pregnant woman
다행히 임신한 척을 하더군요
when we moved here.
우리가 여기로 이사했을 때.
Otherwise, the appearance of a crying baby for no reason
그렇지 않으면 괜히 우는 아기 의 모습
will definitely make people suspicious.
분명 사람들을 의심하게 만들 거예요.
Wait a minute.
잠깐 기다려요.
It should be fortunate that you can't walk
걷지 못해서 다행이다
while on a mountain road,
산길을 가던 중,
then I asked you to pretend to be a pregnant woman.
그러다가 임신한 척 해달라고 했어요 .
Do you think I understand things very carefully?
내가 상황을 아주 주의 깊게 이해하고 있다고 생각하시나요 ?
His Majesty the Imperial Grandson is really good at disguising traces
황손 폐하께서는 흔적을 위장하는데 정말 능숙하십니다
and also remove the shadow.
그림자도 제거하세요.
Why is he crying again?
그 사람은 왜 또 울고 있는 걸까?
Your Majesty the Imperial Grandson, it's time to change the swaddling clothes again.
황손 폐하, 포대기를 다시 갈아입으실 시간입니다.
Why me again?
왜 또 나야?
That's because you understand something very carefully.
그것은 당신이 어떤 것을 아주 세심하게 이해하고 있기 때문입니다.
I'm really scared of you.
난 정말 당신이 무서워요.
Come on, don't cry anymore. Here.
자, 더 이상 울지 마세요. 여기.
Don't cry, okay?
울지 마, 알았지?
Why do you have so much poop?
왜 이렇게 똥이 많아?
- Big boss! - How?
- 빅 보스! - 어떻게?
Grand Master, I have ordered people
그랜드 마스터, 사람들에게 명령을 내렸습니다
to guard the forest closely, but it was almost dark
숲을 엄수하려고 했으나 거의 어두워졌음
and no one came to collect the Military Plates.
그리고 아무도 군용 번호판을 수집하러 오지 않았습니다.
- No one? - Correct.
- 아무도? - 옳은.
I was afraid that Old Master would be worried so went back first.
노사님이 걱정하실까 봐 먼저 돌아갔습니다.
Big Master, according to you, will they hurt Little Young Master
빅 마스터, 당신 말에 따르면 그들이 리틀 영 마스터를 다치게 할 것인가?
if you don't get Military Plates?
군용 번호판을 얻지 못했다면?
(Han Residence)
(한 레지던스)
You have to grow well.
잘 키워야 합니다.
That way, the Emperor's Grandson was not wasted
그래야 황제의 손자가 낭비되지 않았다.
wash a lot of diapers for you.
기저귀를 많이 씻어주세요.
Come on, let's go light a fire.
자, 불을 피우러 가자.
Later, you have to be careful. Don't burn this room down.
나중에는 조심해야 합니다. 이 방을 불태우지 마세요.
- I already know. - Come on.
- 이미 알고 있어요. - 어서 해봐요.
- Fire!
- 불!
Fire?
불?
This is bad, the enemy probably already knows that the Military Plate is fake
이건 나쁘다. 적군은 이미 군용 플레이트가 가짜라는 것을 알고 있을 것이다.
and came to pick up the original Military Plates.
그리고 원래의 군용 번호판을 가지러 왔습니다 .
Quickly send someone to the south courtyard.
빨리 누군가를 남쪽 안뜰로 보내십시오.
Prepare more water to prevent burns.
화상을 예방하려면 물을 더 준비하세요 .
Now, we know the whereabouts of genuine Military Plates.
이제 우리는 정품 군용 번호판의 행방을 알고 있습니다.
However, there were so many arrows and traps set in the yard.
그런데 마당에는 화살과 함정이 너무 많이 설치되어 있었습니다 .
We cannot break through by force.
우리는 강제로 돌파할 수 없습니다.
Let's go back first to think about how.
먼저 돌아가서 방법을 생각해 봅시다.
- Come on.
- 어서 해봐요.
Big boss.
빅 보스.
Unexpectedly, someone deliberately started the fire.
예기치 않게 누군가 고의로 불을 지른 것입니다.
Even more unexpected,
더욱 예상치 못한,
someone returned the Little Young Master to his room.
누군가가 Little Young Master를 그의 방으로 돌려보냈습니다.
Luckily the fire was extinguished.
다행히 불은 진압됐습니다.
Little Young Master is safe and fine.
Little Young Master는 안전하고 괜찮습니다.
This is a two-pronged strategy
이는 양면 전략이다.
deliberately made me go to see the Military Plates.
일부러 나를 밀리터리 플레이트(Military Plates)를 보러 가게 했습니다.
They took advantage of the fire situation
그들은 화재 상황을 이용했다
to make everyone in the residence panic and steal the Military Plates.
거주지의 모든 사람을 당황하게 만들고 군용 번호판을 훔칩니다.
It would be good if they really came to steal the Military Plates.
정말로 군용 번호판을 훔치러 왔으면 좋을 텐데 .
The security of the southern courtyard where the Military Plate was located was very tight.
밀리터리 플레이트가 위치한 남쪽 안뜰의 보안은 매우 삼엄했습니다.
Without 1,800 people, no one could break through.
1,800명이 없으면 누구도 돌파할 수 없습니다.
We already know the existence of Military Plates,
우리는 이미 밀리터리 플레이트의 존재를 알고 있으며,
but supervision is very strict.
하지만 감독은 매우 엄격합니다.
Looks like it would be difficult to steal it.
훔쳐가기는 힘들 것 같습니다.
Since you can't steal secretly,
몰래 훔칠 수는 없으니까 .
we try to outwit them.
우리는 그들을 속이려고 노력합니다.
How about we pretend to be envoys from the Western Border Army
서부 국경군의 사절 인 척하는 건 어때요?
and went to face Han Li?
그리고 한리를 만나러 갔다고?
Can't.
캔트.
The Western Border Army had just returned from losing at Wangzhou City.
서부 국경군은 왕저우(Wangzhou) 시에서 패전을 마치고 막 돌아왔습니다.
Han Li will definitely not be kind to us.
Han Li는 확실히 우리에게 친절하지 않을 것입니다.
We'd better pretend to be the Cui Family Team's emissaries.
우리는 Cui Family Team의 사절인 척하는 것이 좋습니다 .
We go to talk to Han Li that we want to borrow the Jianzhou road
우리는 Jianzhou 도로를 빌리고 싶다고 Han Li와 이야기하러갑니다.
and promises profit for him.
그리고 그에게 이익을 약속합니다.
Han Li is a greedy person.
한리는 탐욕스러운 사람이다.
Your Cui Family Army has a very high reputation.
당신의 Cui Family Army는 매우 높은 평판을 가지고 있습니다.
Most likely he will agree.
아마 그는 동의할 것이다.
Grandson of the Emperor, you are truly sincere and honest.
황제의 손자여, 당신은 진실하고 정직합니다.
We can get Military Plates,
군용 번호판을 얻을 수 있습니다.
as long as Han Li sends people to Jianzhou
Han Li가 Jianzhou에 사람들을 보내는 한
to take Military Plates,
군용 번호판을 가져가려면
at that time we can rob him and kill him in the middle of the road
그때 우리는 그 사람을 훔쳐서 길 한복판에서 죽일 수도 있어
or exchange the fake for the original.
아니면 가짜를 원본으로 바꾸세요.
If you succeed in getting a Military Plate,
밀리터리 플레이트 획득에 성공하면,
Western Border Army and Cui Family Army
서부 국경군 과 추이 가문군
each took one city.
각각 하나의 도시를 차지했습니다.
Always Bingzhou.
항상 빙저우.
We better make a deal.
거래를 하는 게 좋을 것 같아요.
Whichever of us captures or kills Han Li first,
우리 중 한리를 먼저 붙잡거나 죽이는 쪽이
he is the one who will get Bingzhou.
그는 Bingzhou를 얻을 사람입니다.
Whichever of us gets the Military Plate first,
우리 중 누가 먼저 군용 판금을 얻든,
he was the one who got Jianzhou.
그는 Jianzhou를 얻은 사람이었습니다.
What if I capture Han Li and also obtain a Military Plate?
한리를 포획 하고 군용판도 획득하면 어떻게 되나요?
Bingzhou, Jianzhou, everything is yours.
Bingzhou, Jianzhou, 모든 것이 당신 것입니다.
The Western Border Army will not say anything,
서부국경군은 아무 말도 하지 않을 것이다.
vice versa.
그 반대.
Good.
좋은.
If Jianzhou and Bingzhou belonged to the Western Border Army,
Jianzhou와 Bingzhou가 서부 국경군에 속했다면
Jianzhou has always been an important route to the east and north.
Jianzhou는 항상 동쪽과 북쪽으로의 중요한 경로였습니다 .
Later, Cui Family Army military merchants
나중에 Cui Family Army 군사 상인
will use the road to cross the border,
국경을 넘을 때는 도로를 이용하고 ,
The Western Border Force cannot refuse.
서부국경군은 거부할 수 없습니다.
And vice versa.
그 반대.
Clap my hands as a sign of agreement.
동의의 표시로 손뼉을 치세요.
Sir, Chen Xing sent a reply.
Chen Xing 선생님이 답장을 보냈습니다.
Finally, the mark left by Commander He was discovered
드디어 히 사령관이 남긴 흔적이 발견됐다
in a very hidden place in Bingzhou City.
Bingzhou시의 매우 숨겨진 장소에 있습니다 .
Good, very good.
좋아 아주 좋아.
Taozi, you go to Bingzhou City to see Chen Xing,
Taozi, 당신은 Chen Xing을 만나러 Bingzhou City에 가십시오.
and help the Commander.
그리고 사령관을 도와주세요.
Bingzhou was Han Li's territory. People are easily suspicious.
Bingzhou는 Han Li의 영토였습니다. 사람들은 쉽게 의심을 합니다.
If you come bringing a group of soldiers slowly,
천천히 병사들을 데리고 오시면
I'm afraid he will harm the Commander.
그 사람이 사령관에게 해를 끼칠까 두렵습니다 .
Lin.
린.
(Cui Li, General of the Cui Family Army)
(최씨군 장군 추이리)
Brother, why did you come?
형님, 왜 오셨어요?
Lin, you fought outside for several months.
린, 당신은 몇 달 동안 밖에서 싸웠어요.
As an older brother, how could I not worry about you?
형으로서 어떻게 걱정하지 않을 수 있겠습니까?
Now,
지금,
Uncle sent me to the western mountains to take care of something.
삼촌이 나를 서쪽 산으로 보내서 일을 처리하게 하셨다.
I also think that the western mountain is very close to your place
내 생각엔 서쪽 산이 당신 집과 아주 가까운 것 같아요
so I immediately brought my entourage to come to meet you.
그래서 나는 즉시 일행을 데리고 당신을 만나러 왔습니다.
As brothers, we work together to kill the enemy
형제로서 우리는 적을 죽이기 위해 협력합니다
so that Uncle knows that this is his nephew
삼촌이 이것이 그의 조카라는 것을 알 수 있도록
can also achieve brilliant achievements.
눈부신 성과 도 얻을 수 있습니다 .
Brother, your actions violate military orders.
형제여, 당신의 행동은 군사 명령을 위반하는 것입니다.
Lin, just calm down.
린, 진정해.
I've sent someone to report it
신고할 사람을 보냈어요
to Uncle as soon as possible.
가능한 한 빨리 삼촌에게.
I'm sure Uncle will definitely agree.
나는 삼촌이 분명히 동의할 것이라고 확신한다.
Besides, just think about it, if my thousands of troops returned alone,
게다가 생각해 보세요. 내 수천 명의 병력이 홀로 돌아왔다면,
What if something happens while traveling?
여행 중 무슨 일이 생기면 어쩌지 ?
Since you have already reported it to my father,
이미 아버지께 보고하셨으니
set up camp and rest.
캠프를 준비하고 휴식을 취하세요.
The soldiers are still here.
군인들은 아직 여기에 있어요.
What is your plan?
당신의 계획은 무엇입니까?
Brother, since you came here in violation of military orders,
형님, 군사명령을 어기고 여기까지 오셨으니
you have to hold back your troops
병력을 막아야 한다
and may not discuss any military matters.
군사 문제에 대해서는 논의할 수 없습니다 .
Otherwise, when you go back to my father's place,
그렇지 않으면 네가 내 아버지 집으로 돌아갈 때에
accept the punishment for the offense you committed.
당신이 저지른 범죄에 대한 처벌을 받아들이십시오 .
How dare that sick person speak rudely to me.
그 아픈 사람이 감히 나에게 무례하게 말할 수 있겠습니까?
This Cui Lin just happened to be reincarnated with good fortune.
이 추이린은 우연히 행운을 가지고 환생했습니다.
If I were Uncle's son,
내가 삼촌의 아들이라면,
The entire Cui Family Army has long been under my command.
Cui Family 군대 전체가 오랫동안 내 지휘하에있었습니다.
Third Lord, don't be emotional.
셋째 주님, 감정적으로 반응하지 마십시오.
Cui Lin has been sickly and weak since childhood.
추이린은 어릴 때부터 몸이 약하고 몸이 약했습니다 .
He took medication for years. It probably won't last long.
그는 수년간 약을 복용했습니다. 아마도 오래 가지 못할 것입니다.
At that time, the Great General had no sons,
당시 대장군에게는 아들이 없었고,
won't the Cui Family Team be yours?
Cui Family Team이 당신의 팀이 아니겠습니까?
I humbled myself for years.
나는 수년 동안 나 자신을 낮추었습니다.
With the current turbulent situation,
요즘 혼란스러운 상황 속에서
I really can't wait any longer.
정말 더 이상 기다릴 수가 없어요 .
Does Third Master want to...
세 번째 스승님은...
The reason I humbled myself to follow Cui Lin
내가 스스로 겸손하여 최린을 따르게 된 이유
is to act according to the situation.
상황에 따라 행동하는 것입니다.
With one action, I will get rid of
한 번의 조치로 제거하겠습니다.
Cui Lin and also Commander He.
Cui Lin과 He 사령관.
The two of you came here under Young Master Cui's orders
너희 둘은 최영대사의 명령으로 이곳에 왔다
to borrow the Jianzhou road for the Cui Family Army?
Cui Family Army를 위해 Jianzhou 도로를 빌릴 수 있습니까 ?
That's right, we hope Mr. Han agrees.
맞습니다. 한씨도 동의하길 바랍니다.
This is easy to talk about.
이것은 이야기하기 쉽습니다.
However, Military Commander Sun in the capital
그러나 수도의 쑨(孫)군 사령관은
always ordered me strictly to defend the city.
항상 나에게 도시를 방어하라고 엄격하게 명령했습니다.
If I agree to lend it,
내가 빌려주는 데 동의한다면,
it's possible that Commander Sun will punish me.
Sun 사령관이 나를 처벌할 수도 있습니다 .
Since we came to borrow from Mr. Han,
우리는 한씨에게 돈을 빌리러 왔기 때문에
The Cui family had naturally prepared reciprocity.
추이 가문은 자연스럽게 호혜를 준비했다.
Gathering merchants from both cities,
두 도시의 상인들을 모아,
went to Pingliang City and Weiyang where the Cui Family was located
평양시와 최씨 가문이 있는 웨이양으로 갔습니다.
to sell silk.
실크를 팔려고.
As long as Mr. Han agrees to lend it,
한씨가 빌려주기만 하면,
then later,
그럼 나중에,
we will not levy silk tax on traders
우리는 상인들에게 실크세를 부과하지 않을 것입니다
located in both cities.
두 도시 모두에 위치하고 있습니다.
I think Mr. Han definitely understands the tax benefits.
한씨는 세제 혜택을 확실히 이해하고 있다고 생각합니다.
You two came from a long way and it's already late today.
너희 둘은 먼 길에서 왔고 오늘은 이미 늦었다.
How about you rest at my residence while drinking wine?
내 집에서 와인을 마시며 쉬어가는 건 어때요 ?
The team you lead is near here.
당신이 이끄는 팀이 이 근처에 있습니다.
We couldn't stay any longer.
우리는 더 이상 머물 수 없었습니다.
We have to go back as soon as possible to report to Master.
우리는 스승님께 보고하기 위해 가능한 한 빨리 돌아가야 합니다 .
Good. You two, please sit down.
좋은. 두 분은 앉으세요.
Wait for me to discuss this first.
이 문제를 먼저 논의할 때까지 기다려 주세요.
(Kota Wangzhou)
(코타왕저우)
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
Second Brother, why your Western Border Army
둘째 형제, 왜 서부 국경군이 있습니까?
fighting this strangely?
이상하게 싸우나?
Night is coming,
밤이 온다,
we are all outside Wangzhou City to feed mosquitoes.
우리는 모두 모기에게 먹이를 주기 위해 왕저우시 밖에 있습니다 .
Brother Chang'er already said,
Chang'er 형제는 이미 이렇게 말했습니다.
He didn't let us come, but you insisted on coming.
그는 우리가 오는 것을 허락하지 않았지만 당신은 오라고 고집했습니다.
Since it has come, we should obey Brother Chang'er's words.
이것이 왔으니 우리는 창아 형제님의 말씀에 순종해야 합니다.
However, what are we actually doing here?
그런데 우리는 실제로 여기서 무엇을 하고 있는 걸까요?
You said one of the messengers
당신은 메신저 중 하나를 말했다
is Commander He of the Cui Family Army?
허(He) 사령관은 추이 가문 군대(Cui Family Army)의 사령관입니까 ?
That meant she was Young Master Cui's advisor girl
그것은 그녀가 최영사님의 고문 소녀 라는 것을 의미했습니다.
the famous surname He?
유명한 성 그는?
I know food traders
나는 식품 상인을 안다
who had long been connected with the Cui Family Army.
오랫동안 Cui Family Army와 연결되어 왔습니다 .
Just now, when I heard that the Cui Family Army
방금 최씨군이 있다는 소식을 들었을 때
sent a messenger here,
여기로 사자를 보냈어요
I ordered him to check secretly.
나는 그에게 비밀리에 확인하라고 명령했다.
It's confirmed
확인됐다
that she was indeed the counselor's girl.
그녀는 실제로 상담사의 소녀였습니다.
No wonder.
당연합니다.
I'm thinking too
나도 생각 중이야
why is it one of the two envoys from the Cui Family Army
왜 추이 가문 군대의 두 사신 중 한 명입니까?
is a girl in disguise.
변장한 소녀입니다.
Turns out, she was the famous counselor girl surnamed He.
알고 보니 그녀는 He라는 이름의 유명한 상담 소녀였습니다.
I heard too
나도 들었어
that the girl surnamed He was Young Master Cui's confidant
그 성을 가진 소녀는 최영선사의 절친한 친구였다
and often gave him advice.
그리고 종종 그에게 조언을 해주었습니다.
The other messenger had extraordinary tolerance.
다른 메신저는 남다른 관용을 갖고 있었습니다.
At his current age, having such extraordinary tolerance
지금 나이에 이렇게 남다른 관용력을 가지고 있는
also makes me suspicious.
또한 나를 의심하게 만든다.
Why is Mr. Han paying this kind of respect?
한씨는 왜 이런 예의를 표하는 걸까?
Young Master Cui came in such a disguise that it frightened me.
최 젊은 스승님은 너무 변장해서 오셔서 겁이 났습니다.
Since Master Han has revealed Young Master's identity,
한 사부가 영 사부의 정체를 공개한 이후,
we face each other honestly.
우리는 솔직하게 서로를 대합니다.
Master Han took over and built two cities.
한 선생은 두 개의 도시를 점령 하고 건설했습니다.
Master really has a broad outlook.
스승님은 정말 시야가 넓습니다.
This time, Young Master Cui came in person.
이번에는 최영스님이 직접 오셨습니다.
In any case, the matter of borrowing the road can definitely be discussed.
어쨌든 도로를 빌리는 문제는 확실히 논의될 수 있다.
Can be discussed.
논의될 수 있습니다.
Then, thank you very much, Mr. Han.
그럼 한 선생님, 정말 감사드립니다.
Waiter.
웨이터.
- I am here. - Quickly prepare the banquet.
- 나는 여기 있다. - 연회를 빨리 준비하세요.
I will drink wine with Young Master Cui.
최영선생과 함께 와인을 마시겠습니다 .
Good, the first time fighting was really fun.
좋아, 처음의 싸움은 정말 재미있었어.
Correct.
옳은.
Much more exciting than robbing and giving to the poor.
도둑질 해서 가난한 사람들에게 주는 것 보다 훨씬 더 흥미진진한 일입니다 .
- Correct.
- 옳은.
Being a bandit is not as exciting as being a soldier.
도둑이 되는 것은 군인이 되는 것만 큼 흥미롭지 않습니다 .
So true.
정말 그렇습니다.
(Western Frontier) Western Frontier!
(웨스턴 프론티어) 웨스턴 프론티어!
Western Frontier! I'm back!
서부 개척지! 내가 돌아왔다!
Friends!
친구!
Friends, come with me and take back Wangzhou!
친구들이여, 나와 함께 왕저우를 되찾으세요!
(Li) Take back Wangzhou!
(리) 왕저우를 되찾아라!
Young Master Cui, how about this dance?
최영사님, 이 춤 어때요?
I left my hometown and fought in the war,
고향을 떠나 전쟁에 참전했는데
Haven't seen a dance in a long time.
오랫동안 춤을 본 적이 없습니다.
The current scene deserves to be called peace, luxury, and honor.
지금의 장면은 평화, 사치, 명예 라고 할 만하다 .
Muda Muda praises too much.
Muda Muda는 너무 칭찬을 많이 합니다.
Young Master Cui is humble, I feel very moved.
최영스승님은 겸손하셔서 감동이 컸습니다.
Young Master Cui, please enjoy it.
최영스승님, 재미있게 즐겨주세요.
There was a small problem in the back hall, I left for a while and came back soon.
뒷홀에 작은 문제가 있어서 잠시 나갔다가 곧 돌아왔습니다.
Go ahead, Mr. Han.
어서 가세요, 한 선생님.
Military Commander Sun sent a messenger
쑨군 사령관이 사절을 보냈다
and give a very valuable property.
매우 귀중한 재산을 제공합니다 .
I feel a little scared.
조금 무서워요.
(Leader Messenger Sun Jing) The Military Commander said,
(손징(孫晉) 전령사) 군 사령관이 말했다.
it is very difficult for Mr. Han to take responsibility
한씨가 책임을 지는 것은 매우 어렵다
over the two cities and confront the rebels on the Western Border directly.
두 도시를 점령하고 서부 국경의 반군과 직접 대결하세요 .
So, I was specially ordered to send all of these from the capital.
그래서 이 모든 것을 수도에서 보내라는 특별 명령을 받았습니다.
They are all rare treasures carefully selected
모두 엄선된 희귀한 보물입니다
by the Military Commander from his own funds as a tribute to Tuan Han.
Tuan Han에게 경의를 표하기 위해 군 사령관이 자신의 자금으로 제작했습니다 .
Many thanks to the Military Commander.
군 사령관님께 깊은 감사를 드립니다 .
I received the reward for free, I really have to be grateful for it.
무료로 보상을 받았는데 정말 감사해야겠습니다.
Mr. Han is too humble.
한씨는 너무 겸손해요.
I want to know
나는 알고 싶다
Is there a message or order from the Military Commander?
군 사령관의 메시지나 명령이 있습니까 ?
If that's the case, of course there is.
그렇다면 당연히 있습니다.
Actually, the Military Commander sent me here,
사실 군 사령관이 나를 여기로 보냈어요.
firstly because he knows that I have known Mr. Han for a long time,
첫째, 그는 내가 한씨를 오랫동안 알고 지냈다는 것을 알고 있기 때문입니다.
This trip is perfect for us to chat.
이번 여행은 우리가 이야기를 나누기에 딱 좋아요 .
Second, the Military Commander is also worried
둘째, 군 사령관도 걱정한다
with cruel arrows on the battlefield and safety of Lord Han.
전장의 잔혹한 화살 과 한공의 안전으로.
So, I was specially ordered
그래서 특별히 주문했어요
to bring these 12 golden armored guards.
이 황금 갑옷 경비병 12명을 데려오세요 .
I ordered the guards
나는 경비원에게 명령했다
to stay by Tuan Han's side all day.
하루 종일 Tuan Han의 곁에 있기 위해 .
They must protect Master Han completely.
그들은 한 사부를 완전히 보호해야 합니다.
The Military Commander is very caring and kind.
군 사령관은 매우 배려심 많고 친절합니다.
I am so grateful and cannot repay you enough.
너무 감사 하고 보답할 수가 없습니다.
Just by personally leading the guard troops
경비병을 직접 지휘하는 것만으로도
to fight against the Western Border Army
서부 국경군 에 맞서 싸우기 위해
and other traitors,
그리고 다른 반역자들,
I can only repay the kindness of the Military Commander.
군지휘관님의 은혜에 보답할 수 밖에 없습니다 .
The Military Commander's move this time was to force Mr. Big
이번 군 사령관의 움직임은 빅 씨를 강요하는 것이었다.
to be hostile to the two families.
두 가족에게 적대적입니다 .
Otherwise, he couldn't have sent 12 golden-armored guards here.
그렇지 않았다면 황금갑옷 경비병 12명을 이곳에 보낼 수 없었을 것이다 .
They said to protect Mr. Big,
빅씨를 보호하라고 하더군요 .
but actually wants to suppress Master Han.
하지만 실제로는 한사부를 제압하고 싶어합니다.
Sun Jing declared himself Military Commander
손징(孫景)이 스스로를 군 사령관으로 선포
and destroyed the entire Li Family.
리 가문 전체를 파괴했습니다.
He also gave me something called a covenant.
그분은 또한 나에게 언약이라는 것을 주셨습니다.
At that time, I just responded carelessly.
그때 나는 경솔하게 대답만 했을 뿐이었다.
Unexpectedly even exceeding the limit and going further.
의외로 한계를 넘어 더 멀리 나아가기도 한다.
Big Master, the Cui Family members are still in the banquet hall.
빅스승님, 추이가족들은 아직 연회장에 있습니다.
This matter must not be known by the Leader Envoy from Sun Jing.
이 문제는 Sun Jing의 지도자 특사에게 알려져서는 안됩니다 .
We can use the Cui Family members .
Cui Family 구성원을 사용할 수 있습니다.
Cui Yi only had one son.
최이에게는 아들이 하나뿐이었습니다.
Unexpectedly, he even came to my place himself.
뜻밖에도 그 사람이 직접 내 집까지 찾아왔다.
Then, don't blame me if I'm rude.
그럼 내가 무례하다고 해서 비난하지 마세요.
Young Master, you are drunk.
영스승님, 취하셨어요.
I'm not drunk.
나는 취하지 않았습니다.
Something is wrong.
뭔가 잘못되었다.
Young Master, I'll take you back to rest.
영스승님, 제가 다시 편히 쉬게 해 드리겠습니다.
Young Master Cui is drunk.
최영선생은 술에 취했습니다.
Papa Young Master to rest in the guest room!
아빠 영 마스터는 객실에서 쉬세요!
Young Master, wait a minute!
영 마스터님, 잠깐만요!
Young Master Cui, since you guys have come,
최영스승님, 오셨으니
why rush to leave like that?
왜 그렇게 서둘러 떠나?
The way you treat guests is too excessive, right?
손님을 대하는 태도가 너무 과하지 않나요?
If you don't hold the young master today,
오늘 젊은 스승님을 붙잡지 않으면
I couldn't finish my assignment either.
나도 과제를 끝낼 수 없었다 .
I was forced to kill this girl surnamed He
나는 He라는 이름의 이 여자를 강제로 죽여야만 했어요
to explain it to the Master.
마스터에게 설명하려고.
Good. I can stay here, but you have to let go.
좋은. 나는 여기에 머물 수 있지만 당신은 놓아야합니다.
Young Master take it easy.
젊은 스승님, 진정하세요.
If a distinguished guest like Young Master lives in Bingzhou,
영사님 같은 귀빈이 빙저우에 산 다면
the entire Cui Family Army would have no worries.
Cui Family Army 전체가 걱정하지 않을 것입니다.
Of course, I have to let it be
물론 그렇게 놔둬야지
Miss He went back and explained it to General Cui
Miss He는 돌아가서 Cui 장군에게 설명했습니다.
to avoid misunderstanding.
오해를 피하기 위해.
Young Master, go quickly.
영 선생님, 빨리 가세요.
Don't pay attention to these untrustworthy villains .
이런 믿을 수 없는 악당들에게 주의를 기울이지 마세요.
Good! Young Master Cui is very loving and loyal,
좋은! 최영스승은 매우 사랑이 많고 충성스럽습니다.
also appreciate beautiful women.
아름다운 여성에게도 감사합니다.
Young Master take it easy.
젊은 스승님, 진정하세요.
Doors, windows and roof here
여기에 문, 창문 및 지붕이 있습니다.
everything is coated with fine steel so it is very safe.
모든 것이 고급 강철로 코팅되어 있어 매우 안전합니다.
No killer will be able to come.
살인자는 올 수 없습니다.
Prison is still prison,
감옥은 여전히 ​​감옥이다.
why say it that well?
왜 그렇게 잘 말해 ?
Why?
왜?
How can this beautiful place not be a good place?
이 아름다운 곳이 어찌 좋은 곳이 아닐 수 있겠습니까?
Wait a minute.
잠깐 기다려요.
Prepare hot water here.
여기서 뜨거운 물을 준비하세요.
Muda Muda really likes cleanliness.
Muda Muda는 청결을 정말 좋아합니다.
I want to serve him a bath.
나는 그에게 목욕을 시키고 싶다.
Good. I will order people to prepare scented water.
좋은. 나는 사람들에게 향이 나는 물을 준비하라고 명령할 것이다.
Also prepare a thick cloth
두꺼운 천도 준비해주세요
to prevent Young Master from catching cold when bathing.
영스승이 목욕할 때 감기에 걸리지 않도록 하기 위해서입니다.
If our Young Master feels the slightest discomfort
우리 영스승님이 조금이라도 불편함을 느끼신다면
while in Bingzhou City,
빙저우(Bingzhou)시에 있는 동안
The Cui Family's forces will definitely flatten Bingzhou.
추이 가문의 세력은 반드시 빙저우를 무너뜨릴 것입니다.
I'll get a thick cloth for you.
두꺼운 천을 가져다 드릴게요 .
- Young Master, you can take a shower. - Good.
- 영스승님, 샤워를 하셔도 됩니다. - 좋은.
There are people on the roof.
옥상에 사람들이 있어요.
How about this?
이건 어때?
The water temperature is right, how about we shower together?
수온이 적당해요, 우리 같이 샤워 어때요?
Wait a minute.
잠깐 기다려요.
Already. You can talk now.
이미. 이제 얘기하시면 됩니다 .
What are you laughing at?
당신은 무엇을 웃고 있습니까?
I laughed at our first meeting
첫 만남 에 웃었어
it seems similar to now.
지금과 비슷한 것 같아요.
Yes Don't you know that at that time you were so fierce?
응 그땐 네가 그렇게 치열했던 거 몰라 ?
As soon as you come, you invite a fight.
오자마자 싸움을 불러일으킵니다.
Nonsense. Obviously you were the one who attacked first.
무의미한 말. 분명히 먼저 공격한 사람은 당신이었습니다.
Nonsense. Why would I attack you if you don't take my pearls?
내 진주를 가져가지 않으면 내가 왜 당신을 공격하겠습니까 ?
What pearl?
무슨 진주?
That broken belt? I've thrown it away.
그 부러진 벨트? 나는 그것을 버렸습니다.
You...
너...
Why?
왜?
Does the Emperor's Grandson also want to attack me now ?
이제 황제의 손자도 나를 공격하려는 걸까요 ?
Let's talk seriously.
진지하게 얘기해보자.
What plans do you have?
어떤 계획을 갖고 있나요?
What plan?
무슨 계획?
Of course I have to find a way to return to the Cui Family Army,
당연히 최씨군으로 돌아갈 방법을 찾아야 하고 ,
then come back to save you, Young Master.
그럼 다시 돌아와서 당신을 구해주세요, 영 스승님.
Is it true?
사실인가요?
After returning to the Cui Family Army, will you come back to save me?
최씨군으로 돌아온 뒤, 나를 구하러 다시 오실 건가요?
What are you doing? What do you see?
뭐하세요? 무엇이 보이나요?
This Emperor's Grandson's head was priceless.
이 황제의 손자의 머리는 매우 귀중했습니다.
How could I be willing not to come back to save you?
내가 어떻게 당신을 구하러 다시 돌아오지 않을 수 있겠습니까 ?
You're really good at talking.
당신은 정말 말을 잘해요.
I really like.
나는 정말 좋아한다.
Very like.
아주 좋아요.
I didn't think Young Master Cui was such a loving person.
저는 최영대사가 그렇게 사랑이 많은 사람이라고 생각하지 않았습니다.
- Yes. - Just take a shower
- 예. - 그냥 샤워해
can bring out such charm.
이런 매력을 발산할 수 있어요.
I've sent people to watch over there.
그곳을 감시할 사람들을 보냈어요 .
It's just that Miss He is indeed a smart person.
Miss He는 정말 똑똑한 사람입니다.
He not only covered the doors and windows with thick cloth,
두꺼운 천으로 문과 창문을 덮었을 뿐만 아니라 ,
but also cover the copper pipes in the floor
바닥에 있는 구리 파이프 도 덮으세요.
used for eavesdropping.
엿듣는 데 사용됩니다.
I'm worried about our guards
우리 경비원이 걱정돼요
won't be able to hear anything useful.
유용한 정보를 들을 수 없습니다 .
No problem.
괜찮아요.
Unexpectedly, Young Master Cui was so relaxed
예상외로 최영스승님은 너무 여유로웠어요
- and harmonious with their partner. - Correct.
- 파트너와 조화를 이룹니다. - 옳은.
This shows that he is indeed not an ordinary person.
이는 그가 정말 평범한 사람이 아니라는 것을 보여줍니다.
Although Cui Yi only had one son,
최이에게는 아들이 하나밖에 없었지만
he is worth like ten sons.
그는 열 아들만큼 가치가 있습니다.
Very interesting.
매우 흥미로운.
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
I want to ask you.
나는 당신에게 묻고 싶습니다.
Asking what?
무엇을 묻는가?
You still haven't told me your name.
당신은 아직 나에게 이름을 말하지 않았습니다 .
Don't you know that my surname is He?
내 성이 그 사람이라는 걸 모르시나요?
What does your family's Young Master usually call you?
당신 가족의 Young Master는 당신을 주로 뭐라고 부르나요?
Why are you asking that question?
왜 그런 질문을 하는 거죠?
Of course, I was afraid of being discovered when in Han Li's presence.
물론 한리 앞에 있으면 발각될까봐 두려웠어요.
I couldn't possibly call you a girl surnamed He, right?
나는 당신을 He라는 이름의 여자라고 부를 수 없었습니다 .
If you don't want to tell me, I'll just pick a name for you.
알려주고 싶지 않으시면 이름만 골라드릴게요.
What good name can you give me?
나에게 어떤 좋은 이름을 지어줄 수 있나요 ?
Based on your behavior, you will definitely give me
당신의 행동을 보면 당신은 반드시 나에게
bad names like Mao or Gou. [*Means cat or dog]
마오나 고우 같은 나쁜 이름. [*고양이 또는 개를 의미함]
If I pay attention, you look like Mao.
자세히 보니 마오 닮았네요.
You just call me Jin.
그냥 진이라고 불러요.
Tried to fool me again with a fake name.
또 가짜 이름으로 나를 속이려고 했어요 .
I don't want to.
나는 원하지 않는다.
I'd better choose a name for you, your name is Dao
당신의 이름을 선택하는 것이 좋을 것 같습니다 . 당신의 이름은 Dao입니다
or Zhen can too.
아니면 Zhen도 ​​할 수 있습니다.
Why Dao or Zhen?
왜 Dao나 Zhen인가?
Just guess for yourself.
스스로 추측해 보세요.
Dao?
다오?
Zhen?
젠?
You're laughing at me, aren't you?
당신은 나를 비웃고 있는 거죠, 그렇죠?
I pretended to be a pregnant woman twice,
두 번이나 임신한 척을 했고 ,
once my stomach was filled with straw, [*Dao means straw]
내 배가 짚으로 가득 차자, [*도는 짚을 의미합니다]
another filled with pillows. [*Zhen means pillow]
또 하나는 베개로 가득 차 있습니다. [*Zhen은 베개를 의미합니다.]
How dare I.
내가 감히.
You really understand all my origins.
당신은 내 모든 기원을 정말로 이해하고 있습니다.
I just asked your name, you didn't want to tell me.
방금 이름을 물었는데 알려주고 싶지 않더군요.
I'm afraid Han Li will become murderous.
한리가 살인자가 될까봐 두렵습니다 .
If I were killed, I wouldn't even know your name.
내가 죽으면 당신의 이름조차 알지 못할 것입니다.
Isn't that a pity?
안타깝지 않나요?
Very fierce.
매우 치열합니다.
My name is Ying.
제 이름은 잉이에요.
It was a nickname given to me by my mother.
어머니가 지어준 별명이었다 .
(Ying?)
(잉?)
Ying.
잉.
Really good name.
정말 좋은 이름이에요.
- Take a look over there. - Check it out.
- 저기 좀 보세요. - 확인 해봐.
Tie it tightly.
단단히 묶으세요.
- It's still here. - Come on.
- 아직 여기 있어요. - 어서 해봐요.
(Wangzhou)
(왕저우)
Sister, look!
언니, 보세요!
Collect your weapons.
무기를 수집하세요.
Friends,
친구,
- There are new weapons. - How? You guys aren't hurt, right?
- 새로운 무기가 있습니다. - 어떻게? 너희들은 다치지 않았지?
- Nothing. - Give it to him.
- 아무것도 아님. - 그에게 그걸 줘.
Young General Pei, there is something I don't understand.
페이 장군님, 제가 이해하지 못하는 것이 있습니다.
Can I ask you a question?
질문해도 될까요?
Needless to say, let's say.
말할 필요도 없이 말해보자.
I'm confused,
나는 혼란스럽다.
why did the Western Border Army leave Wangzhou?
서부 국경군은 왜 왕저우를 떠났는가?
Then, I was also confused,
그러다가 나도 당황했고,
why do we all follow Young General Pei
왜 우리는 모두 페이 장군을 따르는 걸까요?
back to Wangzhou?
왕저우로 돌아가?
I have discussed this with Shiqi.
나는 이것을 Shiqi와 논의했습니다 .
If the enemy is too strong, we cannot defend Wangzhou.
적이 너무 강하면 왕저우를 방어할 수 없습니다.
The only way is to pretend to retreat,
유일한 방법 은 후퇴하는 척하는 것뿐이다.
then set up a hidden pillar in Wangzhou City,
그런 다음 왕저우시에 숨겨진 기둥을 세웠습니다 .
poisoning soldiers' food and drinking water,
군인들의 음식 과 식수를 중독시키고,
then spread the news
그럼 소식을 퍼뜨려
to shake the soldiers' morale and undermine its foundations.
군인들의 사기를 흔들고 그 기반을 약화시키려는 것입니다.
Lastly, we will work together inside and out
마지막으로 우리는 안팎으로 함께 일할 것입니다.
to retake Wangzhou.
왕저우(Wangzhou)를 탈환하기 위해.
So it turns out.
그래서 밝혀졌습니다.
Of course, soldiers never tire of trickery.
물론 군인들은 속임수에 지치지 않습니다.
Makes sense.
말이된다.
Isn't that right, Chang'er?
그렇지 않나요, 창어?
Come on, let's go into town.
자, 시내로 들어가자.
- Good! - Come on!
- 좋은! - 어서 해봐요!
(Wangzhou) Ayo.
(왕저우) 아요.
Concubine, there is still no news from General Yun Chang.
후궁이시여, 아직 윤창장군의 소식이 없습니다 .
Who knows how things are going with him and the Emperor's First Grandson.
그 와 황제의 첫째 손자가 어떻게 지내는지 누가 알겠습니까 ?
No news is the best news.
어떤 소식도 없는 것이 가장 좋은 소식입니다.
Come on, let's go see Jiang.
자, 강을 만나러 가자.
(Jiang, Concubine of the Former Crown Prince)
(전 왕세자의 후궁 장)
Crown Princess.
왕세자비.
This is not the past,
이건 과거가 아니고,
So don't call me that again.
그러니 다시는 그렇게 부르지 마세요 .
Yes, Concubine Xiao.
응, 샤오후궁.
How is your body condition these few days?
요즘 몸 상태는 어떤가요 ?
I feel fine.
기분이 괜찮아요.
It's just that I worry all day.
그냥 하루종일 걱정이에요.
Don't worry.
괜찮아요.
Today, I come to tell you that I have found the way.
오늘 나는 그 길을 찾았다는 것을 여러분에게 말하러 왔습니다 .
However, you have to wait a few days
다만, 며칠 기다려야 한다
only then can I get you out of the palace quietly.
그래야만 당신을 조용히 궁전 밖으로 데리고 나갈 수 있습니다.
I will never forget Concubine's kindness.
나는 후궁의 친절을 결코 잊지 않을 것입니다.
Quickly stand up.
빨리 일어나세요.
The baby you are carrying is a descendant of the Crown Prince.
당신이 안고 있는 아기는 왕세자의 후손입니다.
Of course I have to find a way to keep you safe.
물론 난 당신을 안전하게 지킬 방법을 찾아야 해요.
Concubine, we cannot linger here.
첩이여, 우리는 여기에 머물 수 없습니다.
I go first.
내가 먼저 간다.
If there's any trouble, you know how to find Aunt Shen.
문제가 생기면 쉔 이모를 찾는 방법을 알잖아요.
Can.
할 수 있다.
- Young Master.
- 젊은 스승님.
Taozi is back.
타오즈가 돌아왔습니다.
Young Master.
젊은 스승님.
Is there any news about the Commander?
사령관에 대한 소식은 없나요?
There is. Chen Xing and I found out
있습니다. Chen Xing과 내가 알게 된 사실
the latest mark left by the Commander.
지휘관이 남긴 마지막 흔적 .
He entered the Han Li Residence.
그는 한리 거주지에 들어갔다.
Kediaman Han Li?
케디아만 한리?
The commander definitely had a plan when he entered Han Li's Residence.
사령관은 한리의 집에 들어갈 때 확실히 계획을 세웠습니다 .
I also tried to sneak inside, but it was heavily guarded.
나도 몰래 들어가려고 했으나 경비가 삼엄했다.
I was afraid that the enemy would become alert so came out first.
적이 경계할까봐 먼저 나섰습니다.
I'm back to report
신고하러 돌아왔습니다
Chen Xing stayed in Bingzhou City, waiting to pick up the Commander.
Chen Xing은 Bingzhou City에 머물면서 사령관을 데리러 오기를 기다리고 있습니다.
Apart from that, the secret report said
그 외에도 비밀 보고서에 따르면
that the leader's envoy sent by Sun Jing also arrived in Bingzhou.
Sun Jing이 보낸 지도자의 사절 도 Bingzhou에 도착했습니다.
Reportedly, he came there bearing gifts for Han Li.
그는 한리를 위한 선물을 들고 찾아온 것으로 알려졌다 .
He carried two large chests of goods, as well as 12 gold-armored guards.
그는 두 개의 큰 물품 상자 와 12명의 황금 갑옷 경비병을 운반했습니다.
Han Li, the cunning villain,
교활한 악당 한리(Han Li)
always try to play both sides without offending anyone.
항상 누구에게도 불쾌감을 주지 않고 양쪽 측면을 모두 플레이하려고 노력하십시오 .
(Which)
(어느)
Taozi, take the flag of this letter and go to the city in disguise.
도자여, 이 편지의 깃발을 가지고 변장하고 도시로 가십시오.
Give the letter flag to Chen Xing
Chen Xing에게 편지 깃발을 건네주세요
and asked him to meet Han Li properly
한리를 제대로 만나자고 하더군요
in the name of Cui Family Team Leader Envoy .
Cui Family 팀 리더 Envoy의 이름으로 .
Remember to act according to the situation.
상황에 따라 행동하는 것을 잊지 마십시오 .
It would be even better if you could take advantage of the messenger sent by Sun Jing.
Sun Jing이 보낸 메신저를 활용하시면 더욱 좋습니다 .
If Han Li dares to detain someone, we must ask him,
한리가 감히 누군가를 구금하려 한다면 우리는 그에게 물어봐야 합니다.
to see if our team agrees or not.
우리 팀이 동의하는지 확인하기 위해 .
These are flowers that were just picked today.
오늘 막 따온 꽃들이에요 .
The Old Master said that the Young Master was a graceful person.
늙은 스승은 젊은 스승이 우아한 사람이었다고 말했습니다.
Can't ignore
무시할 수 없다
food, clothing, and daily life Tuan Muda.
음식, 의복, 일상 생활 Tuan Muda.
He specifically asked me
저한테 구체적으로 물어보셨어요
sent these flowers for Young Master to enjoy.
Young Master가 즐길 수 있도록 이 꽃을 보냈습니다 .
Thank you very much. You guys are really considerate.
매우 감사합니다. 정말 배려심이 많으시네요.
However, why didn't your Great Master keep his promise?
그런데 당신의 위대한 스승은 왜 약속을 지키지 않았습니까?
At that time, he clearly said that if I surrendered,
그때 그는 내가 항복하면
he will let it go.
그는 그것을 놓아줄 것이다.
Why not keep the promise?
왜 약속을 지키지 않는 걸까요?
Young Master, if you say that, you blame our Grand Master.
영스승님, 그렇게 말씀하시면 우리 그랜드마스터를 탓하시는 겁니다.
Our Grand Master has promised.
우리 그랜드 마스터가 약속했어요.
Young Master, you are very honorable.
젊은 스승님, 정말 존경스럽습니다.
Meanwhile, all our waiters are rude and careless workers.
한편, 우리 웨이터는 모두 무례하고 부주의한 직원입니다.
We are afraid to ignore the Young Master.
우리는 Young Master를 무시하는 것을 두려워합니다.
This Miss He is a person who is considerate towards Young Master.
이 미스씨는 영스승을 배려하는 사람이다 .
If you live here,
만약 당신이 여기에 산다면,
he could of course serve the Young Master well.
물론 그는 젊은 스승을 잘 섬길 수 있었습니다.
You're really good at talking.
당신은 정말 말을 잘해요.
Please enjoy, Young Master. I won't bother you anymore.
즐겨주세요, 영 마스터님. 나는 더 이상 당신을 귀찮게하지 않을 것입니다.
Do not move.
이동하지 않습니다.
You're very relaxed, aren't you?
당신은 매우 편안하지 않습니까?
After all, I'm stuck here and have nothing to do.
결국 나는 여기에 갇혀서 할 일이 없다.
How about playing with me?
나랑 놀아주는 게 어때?
Good.
좋은.
In that case, it would be more fun if there were prizes.
그럴 땐 상품도 있으면 더 재미있을 것 같아요.
A gift?
선물?
Let's make it like this.
이렇게 만들어 보겠습니다.
If I win, you give me a hairpin on your head
내가 이기면 머리에 비녀를 줘
in exchange for my pearls.
내 진주와 교환하세요.
Then, what if you lose?
그러다가 지면 어떡하지?
If you lose, you just give me half the food.
잃으면 음식의 절반만 주세요.
Who said I would give you groceries?
내가 식료품을 주겠다고 누가 말했습니까 ?
♪If you forget the fire of love you once had♪
♪ 한때 느꼈던 사랑의 불길을 잊어버리신다면 ♪
♪Memories will be destroyed and drowned♪
♪기억은 파괴되어 익사합니다♪
♪Your heart is full of color♪
♪당신의 마음은 다채로워요♪
♪Makes it hard for me to forget our relationship♪
♪우리 관계를 잊기 힘들어요 ♪
♪If longing is never left behind♪
♪그리움이 결코 버리지 않는다면♪
♪Hoping to return to the first time we met♪
♪ 처음 만났던 그때로 돌아가고 싶어 ♪
♪The destined warmth I want to leave you♪
♪ 당신에게 남기고 싶은 운명의 온기 ♪
♪If love can remember we once promised♪
♪사랑이 기억할 수 있다면 우리는 한때 약속했었죠♪
♪Even though this love hurts me, I will still live for you♪
♪이 사랑이 나에게 상처를 주더라도 나는 여전히 당신을 위해 살아갈 것입니다 ♪
♪Pulling out the limits of memory, waiting is the hardness of my heart♪
♪기억의 한계를 끌어내는 것, 기다림이 내 마음의 단단함♪
♪If love can remember our promise♪
♪사랑이 우리의 약속을 기억할 수 있다면♪
♪Reverse karma, don't regret ever loving you♪
♪역카르마여, 당신을 사랑한 것을 후회하지 마세요♪
♪I'm willing to give you my heart and wait for your answer♪
♪당신에게 내 마음을 전하고 당신의 대답을 기다릴 의향이 있습니다 ♪
♪If love can remember our promise♪
♪사랑이 우리의 약속을 기억할 수 있다면♪
♪Reverse karma, don't regret ever loving you♪
♪역카르마여, 당신을 사랑한 것을 후회하지 마세요♪
♪I'm willing to give you my heart and wait for your answer♪
♪당신에게 내 마음을 전하고 당신의 대답을 기다릴 의향이 있습니다 ♪